

Personal Profile

Name:	Charlie Liang 梁华成		
Gender:	Male		
Citizenship:	Chinese		
Require Work Visa:	N		
Notice Period:	One month		

Education

Year	University/School	
2011–2015	Wuyi University, China	
	Bachelor of Network Engineering	

Skills

Language:	English, Mandarin, Cantonese		
Technical/Soft Skill &	•	3yrs working experience in software industry (including full	
Domain:		time internship from 2014);	
	•	Basic: Java, SSH2, Jquery Json, Ajax	
	•	DB: MySQL, Oracle	
	•	System: Windows ,Linux	



Summary of qualifications

Charlie has worked as a Java developer for three years and has join some really important projects. For example, project iUpload, Gise App Management System and Eshop. He is versed in J2EE technique and SSH2. Besides, he is a fast learner and has great interest in learning new technologies. He is interesting in finance industry and has a good sense of team spirit and good communication skills.

Professional Experience

July 2016 - Present HSBC, Guangzhou (GLTC)

Acting as software engineer in ADM utility.

Major project:

July 2016 - April 2017 iUpload

This project is made for HongKong and Shanghai Banking Corporation. It is a certificate handle system and let user input the certificate from the website and transfer the material to the other system or sending a special email. Use Spring+Hibernate+webservice as server technology, and use Oracle as database. This system support more than 5 countries(MYH, HK,CHN, SG) in the world and it is stable and good at performance. So we get an award at the end of 2016. This project is really important and wonderful as well as efficient.

-Responsibility:

- 1. Code review. As an important system of the bank, iUpload need to be really stable and safe, we need to review the code wrote by the others and I am the reviewer.
- 2. Code management, I am responsible on our team's code management. Including the synchronizing code and handle the conflict.
- 3. Develop the function module and communicate with other team. I have developed daily email, refactoring the configuration to database and so on.
- -Development technology: Spring, Hibernate, Web Service, Oracle, spring job, spring batch, Spring scheduler, RTC, Jenkins, G3, Websphere.

Leaving reason: Move to Shenzhen city due to family reason.

Aug 2015 - July 2016 Baosi technology co., LTD

Acting as Java Developer in IT Dept.

Major project:

Dec 2015 –June 2016 Gise App Management System



This project is made for Guangzhou iron and Steel Technology Co., Ltd. It is a inner system and it is let user log in the system and manager the users, push message and query the data . Use Spring+Hibernate+Struct as server technology, and use Json as data transport. Database is oracle. This website is completed and the user is feel good while use it.

-Responsibility: Responsible for users module, push module and some others function. I design and implement the function. Besides, I am responsible for the release and find the solve method when there exist issue. All in all, I need to be responsible for our system.

-Development technology: Spring, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, Ajax, JQuery, JavaScript, Oracle, SVN, Tomcat.

Leaving reason: Turn to finance IT industry.

Feb 2014 - June 2015 Pactera, Guangzhou

Acting as Java Intern for HSBC project.

Major project:

Apr 2015 – Jun 2015 Flower Website

Lead developer, primarily responsible for database design and development. The system is website as a social communication platform, similar to "Baihe". The system involves 3 functional modules of Register and Log in/out, Message Sending and Receiving, and User Search.

-Development technology: Maven, Bootstrap, SpringMVC, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, Ajax, JQuery, JavaScript, Oracle.

Apr 2015 - May 2015 Hotel Ordering System

Primarily responsible for framework, database design, and development. The system is a management system of hotel ordering. The system involves 3 functional modules of Register and Log in/out, Order Management, User Log.

-Development technology: Spring, Struts, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, Ajax, JQuery, JavaScript, MySQL

Jul 2014 – Nov 2014 E-Shop

Lead developer, primarily responsible for database design and development of modules "Register and Log in/out" and "Order Management". The system is shopping website. The



system involves 3 functional modules of Register and Log in/out, User Administration, Order Management, Comment Management.

-Development technology: JSP, Servlet, Tomcat, MySQL

Training experience

Jul 2014 – Nov 2014 Java Course Training – Guangzhou Tuosheng Corporation limited.

Certification

CET 4